Mello, Michael; Papers apap287
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Publications, 1979-2006; 6; 4.4 cubic ft.
  - Dead Wrong - Button, 1997 (Oversized 1, Item 2)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft (1 of 3), 1995 September 21 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft (2 of 3), 1995 September 21 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft (3 of 3), 1995 September 21 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Dead Wrong- Draft, ca. 1995 (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 1 (6-Publications), Folder 25)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts (1 of 3), Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts (2 of 3), Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts (3 of 3), Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Dead Wrong- Drafts, Undated (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Dead Wrong Review, 1997 December 29 (Box 2 (6-Publications), Folder 18)
  - "Death and His Lawyers: Why Joseph Spaziano Owes His Life to the Miami Herald- and Not to Any Defense Lawyer and Judge" by Michael Mello- Vermont Law Review, Fall, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Death Penalty Casebook- Table of Contents, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Death Work- Copy Edits and Page Proofs (1 of 2), 2002 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Death Work- Copy Edits and Page Proofs (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Death Work- Draft (1 of 2), 2002 June 10 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Death Work- Draft (2 of 2), 2002 June 10 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Death Work by Ross Klaven- Screenplay Based on The Wrong Man, 2005 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Death Stats, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 8)
  - " Death-to-Life Overrides: Saving the Resources of the Florida Supreme Court" by Michale L. Radelet and Michael Mello- Florida State University Law Review, Summer, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 9)
  - " Defunding Death" by Michael Mello- American Criminal Law Review, Summer, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 10)
  - "Defunding Death" - Draft, 1991 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 11)
  - "Defunding Death"- Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 12)
  - "Defunding Death"- Draft, 1993 November 04 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 13)
  - "Defunding Death"- Draft, 1994 August 16 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 14)
  - "Defunding Death"- Draft, Undated (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Draft Article for Miami Herald, 1997 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 16)
  - " Ed Kennedy's Rainbow, Steve Booker's Poetry and Dick Jorandby's Soul: Remarks for a Fundraiser for Death Penalty Focus of California" by Michael Mello- Vermont Law Review, 2002 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 17)
  - " Espinosa v. Florida: Constitutional Hurrican or Lamdent Breeze"- Draft, ca.1992 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 18)
  - " Executing Rapists: A Reluctant Essay on the Ethics of Legal Scholarship" by Michael Mello- William and Mary Journal of Women and the Law, 1997 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 19)
  - " Executing Those Who Kill Blacks: An Unusual Case Study" by Michael L. Radelet and Michael Mello- Mercer Law Review, 1986 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 20)
  - " Facing Death Alone: The Post- Conviction Attorney Crisis on Death Row" by Michael Mello- The American University Law Review, 1988 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 21)
  - " Innocence and Capital Punishment"- Draft, ca. 1995 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 22)
  - "'In the Years When Murder Wore the Mask of Law': Diary of a Capital Appeals Lawyer" by Michael Mello - Vermont Law Review, 2000 Spring (Oversized 1, Item 1)
  - " Is There A Federal Constitutional Right to Counsel in Capital Post-Conviction Proceedings?" by Mihcael Mello- The Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology, 1989 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 23)
  - " Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello, 1979-1990; 1992; Undated (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 24)
  - " A Letter on a Lawyer's Life of Death" by Michael Mello- South Texas Law Review, 1997 March (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 25)
  - Material Edited out of Unknown Draft, Undated (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 26)
  - " Mello v. Government- Imposed Mortality"- Loquitur, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 27)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1987; 1995-2001; 2005-2006 (Box 3 (6-Publications), Folder 28)
  - " The Non-Trial of the Century: Representation of the Unabomber" by Michael Mello- Vermont Law Review, 2000 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 1)
  - " On Metaphors, Mirrors, and Murders: Theodore Bundy and the Role of Law" by Michael Mello- New York University Review of Law and Social CHange, 1991 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 2)
  - " On Metaphors, Mirrors, and Murders"- Draft, Undated (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 3)
  - "Outlaw Attorney"- Draft (1 of 2), 1995 December 12 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 4)
  - " Outlaw Attorney" -Draft( 2 of 2), 1995 December 12 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 5)
  - " Outlaw Attorney"- Draft, 1995 December 22 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 6)
  - " Outlaw Attorney"- Draft, 1995 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 7)
  - "Outlaw Attorney"- Draft, Undated (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 8)
  - "Outlaw Attorneys: The Duties of a Law- Abiding Death Raw Post- Conviction Lawyer" by Michael Mello- Yale Version, Undated (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 9)
  - " Outlaw Executive: 'Crazy Joe', The Hypnotized Witness and the Mirage of Clemency in Florida" by Michael Mello- Journal of Contemporary Law, 1997 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Photocopies of Book Covers by Michael Mello, Undated (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 11)
  - " Raising Holy Hell: John Brown's Trial Lawyers (and Ted Kaczynski's Lawyer) and the politics od the Instantly Defense" by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Review, 1998 July-August (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 12)
  - " The Real Capital Punishment: The (Shotgun) Marriage Between Social Science and Litigation, and the Inviting Footnote in Brown v. Texas" by Michael Mello- Criminal Law Bulletin, 1999 March- April (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 13)
  - " Right to Counsel in Death Penalty" - Draft Outline, 1987 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 14)
  - " Rough Justice: The Capital Habeas Corpus (Anti) Jurisprudence of Judge Robert S. Vance" by Michael Mello- Draft and Research, 1985-1991; Undated (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 15)
  - " Rough Justice: Reflections on the Capital Habeas Corpus (Anti) Jurispurdence of Judge Robert S. Vance" by Michael Mello- Alabama Law Review, 1991 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Statement of Michael Mello Before the Committee on the Judiciary United State Senate Concerning Death Penalty Legislation, 1989 September 27 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Statement of Michael Mello before the Committee on the Judiciary, Vermont House of Representatives, concerning H830-Draft, 2006 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Statistics/ Death Penalty by Maxwell/Mello, 1991 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 19)
  - " The Sunshine Executioner: A Review of Among the Lowest of the Dead: The Culture of Death Row by David von Drehle" by Michael Mello- Journal of Contemporary Law, 1997 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 20)
  - " Suspending Justice: The Unconstitutionality of the Proposed Six- Month Time Limit of the Filing of Habeas Corpus Petitions by State Death Row Inmates" by Michael Mello and Donna Duffy- New York University Review of Law and Social Change, 1990- 1991 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 21)
  - " Taking Coldwell v. Mississippi Seriously: The Unconstitutionality of Capital Statutes that Divide Sentencing Responsibilty Between Judge and Jury" by Michael Mello- Boston College Law Review, 1989 March (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 22)
  - " Ted Kaczynski's Diary" by Michael Mello and Paul Perkins- Vermont Law Review, Fall, 1997 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 23)
  - The United States of America versus Theodore John Kaczynski: Ethics, Power and the Invention of the Unabomber - Thurlow Gordon Lecture Poster, 1999 (Flat-file 3)
  - Unknown Drafts, Undated (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Unlabeled Appendix, Undated (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 25)
  - " Who is the Real 'Outlaw' Here: Joseph Spaziano, Florida Governor Lawton Chilos, or the State and Federal Judiciaries?"- Drafts ( 1 of 3), 1995 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 26)
  - " Who is the Real 'Outlaw' Here: Joseph Spaziano, Florida Governor Lawton Chilos, or the State and Federal Judiciaries?"- Drafts ( 2 of 3), 1995 (Box 4 (6-Publications), Folder 27)
  - " Who is the Real 'Outlaw' Here: Joseph Spaziano, Florida Governor Lawton Chiles, of the State and the Federal Judiciaries?"- Drafts (3 of 3)-Drafts, 1995 (Box 5 (6-Publications), Folder 1)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft, 1997 (Box 5 (6-Publications), Folder 2)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft ( 1 of 2), Undated (Box 5 (6-Publications), Folder 3)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft ( 1 of 2), Undated (Box 5 (6-Publications), Folder 4)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft, Undated (Box 5 (6-Publications), Folder 5)
  - The Wrong Man- Draft, Undated (Box 5 (6-Publications), Folder 6)
  - The Wrong Man: A Trust Story of Innocence on Death Row - Poster, 2001 (Map-tube 1)
- Research Files, 1800-2004; 7; 14 cubic ft.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains files associated with Michael Mellos research for his publications, his legal work, or his classroom work. The research files cover a range of topics including juveniles on death row, jury override, and the adequate representation for indigent inmates and represent legal materials, academic articles, newspaper articles, and correspondence regarding various cases and legal issues.
  - The Bartkos Exception to the Dual Sovereighty Doctorine, 1992 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 34)
  - Bas v. Tingy, 1800 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 35)
  - Beasley v. Holland, 1986 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 36)
  - Berea College v. Kentucky, 1908 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 37)
  - Bill Tracking Reports for Various U.S. States Concerning Juveniles and the Death Penalty, 2003-2004 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 38)
  - Blake v. Zant, 1981 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 39)
  - Blystone v. Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 40)
  - Bounds v. Smith, 1976-1977 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 41)
  - Bowden v. Francis, 1984 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 42)
  - Boyde v. California, 1988; 1990 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 43)
  - Brady v. Maryland, 1963 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 44)
  - Joseph Green Brown, 1985; 1987 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 45)
  - Brown v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 46)
  - Brown v. Kemp- USDC, GA- Petition for Writ of Habeas Corpus, 1988 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 47)
  - Bryan v. Koch, 1980 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 48)
  - In the Shadow of the Capital: Childhood hunger in Washington, D.C., Undated (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 49)
  - Burch v. Florida, 1988 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 50)
  - Bush v. Texas, 1963 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 51)
  - Butler v. Aiken, 1989 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 52)
  - Cabana v. Bullock, 1985 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 53)
  - Calder v. Bull, 1798 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 54)
  - Bobby Caldwell, 1984-1985 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 55)
  - California Appellate Project- Program Description, 1984 (Box 1 (7-Research Files), Folder 56)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1989 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 1)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, ( 1 of 2), 1990 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 2)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, ( 2 of 2), 1990 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 3)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1991 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 4)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1992 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 5)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1993 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 6)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1994 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 7)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1995 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 8)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1996 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 9)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1997 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 10)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 1998 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 11)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 1 of 2), 1999 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 12)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 2 of 2), 1999 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 13)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 1 of 2), 2000 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 14)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP ( 2 of 2), 2000 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 15)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 2001 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 16)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 2002 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 17)
  - California Appellate Project, RECAP, 2003 (Box 2 (7-Research Files), Folder 18)
  - Cannon v. Unversity of Chicago, 1979 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 1)
  - Capital Collateral Representative-Presentation to Senate Appropriations Subcommittee, 1987 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 2)
  - Capital Defender Office- Beginnings and Description, 1995 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 3)
  - Capital Defender Office- Creation, Undated (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 4)
  - Capital Defender Office- Funding, 1986; 1995-1996 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 5)
  - Capital Defender Office- Governor's Budget Proposal, 1995 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 6)
  - Capital Defender Office- Potential Problems, 1995-1996 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 7)
  - Capital Losses: The Price of the Death Penalty for New York State- Public Defense Backup Center, 1982 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 8)
  - "Capital Punishment as a System" by Jack Greenberg, 1982 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 9)
  - "Capital Punishment for Minors: An Eighth Amendment Analysis" by Helene B. Greenwald, 1983 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 10)
  - "Capital Sentencing in Kentucky: An Examination of Juvenile Case Characteristics" by Vito and Keil, 1988 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 11)
  - Card v. Dugger, 1987 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 12)
  - Carey v. Garrison, 1975 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 13)
  - Carnes Disqualification Research, 1993 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 14)
  - Cases of Kids on Death Row, 1968; 1979; 1982-1984; 1987 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 15)
  - Cave v. State, 1988 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 16)
  - Certiorari Improvidently Granted, 1916; 1924; 1944; 1955; 1959-1963 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 17)
  - Certiorari Improvidently Granted, 1967-1972; 1977; 1981 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 18)
  - The Challenge of Crime in a Free Society: A Report by the President's Commission on Law Enforcement and Administration of Justice, 1967 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 19)
  - Chaney v. Lewis, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 20)
  - The Changing Legal World of Adolescence by Franklin E. Zimring, 1982 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 21)
  - Changing Youth in a Changing Society by Michael Rutter ( 1 of 2), 1980 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 22)
  - Changing Youth in a Changing Society by Michael Rutter ( 2 of 2), 1980 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 23)
  - Chief Judge Oakes, US CA 2nd Circuit, Hearings on S.635, 1991 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 24)
  - The Child and Death edited by Olle Jane V. Sahlec, 1978 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 25)
  - Childhood and Society by Erik H Erikson- Chapter 7, 1963 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 26)
  - "Children and Death: From the School Setting Viewpoint" by Delphie J. Fredlond, 1977 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 27)
  - Children's Conception of Death by Richard Lonetto, 1980 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 28)
  - "Children's Liberation and the New EgalHananism: Some Reservations About Abandoning Youth to their 'Rights' " by Bruce C. Hafen, 1976 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 29)
  - "Civic Virtue and the Feminine Voice in Constitutional Adjudication" by Suzanna Sherry, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 30)
  - "Civil Disobedience and Operation Rescue: A Historical and Theoretical Analysis" by John W. Whitehead, 1991 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 31)
  - "Civil Disobedience and the Lawyer's Obligation to the Law" by Judith A. McMorrow, 1991 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 32)
  - "Civil Law Regulation of Reproductive Technologies: New Laws for the New Biology?" by Joan Bercovitch, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 33)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1984- H.R. 5490 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 34)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1984- S.2568- Part 1 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 35)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1984- S.2568- Part 2 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 36)
  - Civil Rights Restoration Act of 1985, 1986 (Oversized 1, Item 3)
  - Clisby v. Jones, 1990-1991 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 37)
  - Coker v. Georgia, 1976 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 38)
  - Coleman v. Saffle, 1989 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 39)
  - Coleman v. Thompson, 1991 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 40)
  - "Collateral Post Conviction Remedies in Florida" by Gene D. Brown, 1968 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 41)
  - Collier v. State, 1985 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 42)
  - "Combatting Racial Violence: A Legislative Propasal"- Havard Law Review, 1988 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 43)
  - Commentary on Death Penalty in NY, 1994-1995 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 44)
  - "Comments on Women's Law in Scandinavia" by Agnete Weis Bentzon, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 45)
  - "Competence for Execution Role can Exact Personal Price" by Kathleen Fisher, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 46)
  - "The Concept of the Doctrine of the Court in Constitutional Law" by Earl M. Maltz, 1982 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 47)
  - Confronting Youth Crime- Report of the Twentieth Century Fund Task on Sentencing Policy Toward Young Offenders: Background Paper by Franklin E. Zimring, 1978 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 48)
  - "The Construction of the United States: Contemporary Ratification" by William J. Brennon, JR., 1986 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 49)
  - "Constitutional Adjudication and the Death Penalty: A View From the Court" by William J. Brennan, JR.,-1986 Oliver Wendell Holmes, Jr. lecture (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 50)
  - "Constitutional Jurisprudence of History and Natural Law: Complimentary of Rival Modes of Discourse?" by C.M.A McCauliff, 1988 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 51)
  - "Constitutional Law- Eighth Amendment-cruel and unusual Punishment-The Prejudice effect of the Prosecutor's Comment on the Capital Sentencing Jury"- Mississipi Law Journal, 1985 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 52)
  - Constitutional Law- Recent Developments, 1981 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 53)
  - Constitutionality of the Death Penalty in New York, 1995 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 54)
  - "Contingency and Community in Normative Practice" by Steven L. Winter, 1991 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 55)
  - "Conventional Morality and Judical Standards" by Wojciesh Sadurks, 1987 (Box 3 (7-Research Files), Folder 56)
  - Cooper v. Dugger, 1988 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 1)
  - Counsel for Indigent Habeas Petitioner, 1991 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 2)
  - Crime and Human Nature by Wilson and Herrnstein- Excerpt, 1985 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 3)
  - Crime in the US- FBI Uniform Crime Reports, 1979 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 4)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1963 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 5)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1963 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 6)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1964 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 7)
  - Criminal Justice Act, 1985-1986 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 8)
  - "Criminal Procedure- An Indigent's Constitutional Right to a State- Paid Expert", 1980 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 9)
  - Cumming v. Richmond County Board of Education, 1899 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 10)
  - Curfew Statutes, 1977; 1984; 1987 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 11)
  - "Darkness on the Edge of Town: The Contributions of John Hart Ely to Constitutional Theory" by Mark Tushnet, 1980 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 12)
  - "Deadly Mistakes: Harmless Error in Capital Sentencing" by James C. Scoville, 1987 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 13)
  - Death- Innonece and the Law of Habeus Corpus" by Stephen P. Garvey, 1992 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 14)
  - "Death Penalty" by Criag Barnard, 1989 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 15)
  - "The Death Penalty and Juveniles" by Charles Z. Smith, 1992 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 16)
  - "Death Penalty Cases", 1987 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 17)
  - The Death Penalty in America (Third Edition)- Hugo Adam Bedau- Excerpts, 1982 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 18)
  - The Death Penalty in 2003: Year End Report- Death Penalty Information Center (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 19)
  - Death Row Representation, 1994-1996 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 20)
  - Death Sentences Imposed, 1988 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 21)
  - "The Decency of Capital Punishment For Minors: Contemporary Standards and the Dignity of Juveniles" by Lawrence A. Vanore, 1986 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 22)
  - "Deciding Who Dies" by Stephen Gillers, 1980 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 23)
  - "Defining Due Process of Law: The Case of Mr. Justice Hugo L. Black" by Roger W. Haigh, 1972 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 24)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1948; 1964; 1966; 1971; 1973-1974 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 25)
  - "Defunding Death"-Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 26)
  - "Defunding Death"-Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 27)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 28)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 29)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 30)
  - "Defunding Death"- Research, 1976-1989; 1994; Undated (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 31)
  - Dual Prosecution and Successive Federal Prosecution Policies, 1989 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 32)
  - Determining Eligibility For Appointed Counsel in New York State- Public Defense Backy Center, 1944 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 33)
  - Devier v. Kemp, 1987 (Box 4 (7-Research Files), Folder 34)
  - The Dilemmas of Liberal Constitutionalism by Mark Tushnet, 1981 (Box 5 (7-Research Files), Folder 1)
  - "Disorder in the Court: The Death Penalty and the Constitution" by Robert A. Burt, 1987 (Box 5 (7-Research Files), Folder 2)